





# Software Engineer

#### WHO AM I?

Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in software development. Experienced in both defining and following best practices, making architecture decisions and communicating with partners and clients.

Very adaptable to different areas and technologies such as 3D applications, desktop, backend, frontend, databases, DevOps and Infrastruture

I like to be challenged.





#### **EXPERIENCE**

05/2021 - now

#### Technical Lead

Ocean Infinity

Ocean Infinity is a marine robotics company that deploys autonomous technologies at scale to capture ocean data and deliver maritime solutions. In 2021, Ocean Infinity acquired Abyssal. Shortly after the acquisition, I was asked to assume the role of Tech Lead. I'm responsible for:

- The architecture, design, code quality, system stability and resiliency of our software solutions.
- Understanding the broader context and setting an adequate technical roadmap for our teams
- · Collaborating with the team to identify and fix technical problems.
- · Guiding the team through technical issues and challenges.

## 03/2012 - 2021

## Software Engineer/Senior Software Engineer

Abyssal S.A.

Abyssal provides 3D Visualization, Simulation and Digitalization capabilities for subsea operations. Was there since the company was 1 month old. Helped grow the company. Had a crucial role in building most of the software ecosystem.

- · Design desktop applications architecture and build them in WPF and UE4.
- Design and implement data synchronization mechanisms.
- · Design and implement backend services and frontend (SPA).
- · Design and deploy AWS infrastructure as code.
- Work with PostgreSQL databases.
- · Implement CI/CD solutions.
- Review patents before submission.
- Define and plan products roadmap. Occasional Scrum Master role.
- · Client contact for technical demonstrations and systems integration.
- Define and review development best practices and processes.
- Describe software development practices and the full ecosystem architecture in audit-like events for partners.

Desktop: C# / WPF / C++ / WinAPI / UnrealEngine4
Webdev: C# / Python / ASP.NET Core / TypeScript / Angular / RabbitMQ
DevOps: Docker / Jenkins / Terraform / bash / TeamCity

#### 2010 – 2012 Software developer

NDrive

NDrive develops turn-by-turn GPS.

Worked to build and deliver NDrive v11, including its first tablet port. Was also part of the initial teams that rewrote NDrive from scratch for its next major release.

C++ / Objective-C / Cocoa Touch / Java

## **EDUCATION**

July 2018 VISUM 2018 - VISion Understanding and Machine intelligence INESC TEC

VISUM is a summer school about Computer vision and machine Learning. It is comprised of lec-

tures from industry and academia and hands on exercises.

It also has a challenge where teams compete with each other, which our team won.

2004 – 2010 Master in Informatics and Computing Engineering Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto

Advanced instruction in Informatics and Computation Engineering.

Master Thesis - "Exploiting Opponent Behavior in Multi-agent Systems"